Guide to the Peter Viereck papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Reviews and Criticism of Viereck's Work, 1940s-2003
  - Shame and Glory--Reviews by Stefan George, 1947-1968 (Box 113)
  - Strike Through the Mask!, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Terror and Decorum, 1948-1949 (Box 3, 14)
  - Tide and Continuities, 1990s (Box 102)
  - The Unadjusted Man, 1956-2003 (Box 19, 110-111)
  - Interview for Mount Holyoke College Senior Yearbook, 1990 (Box 95, 110)
  - Published and Unpublished Criticism of Viereck's Poetry (Box 4)
  - Archer in the Marrow--Reviews by Robert McDowell and others, undated (Box 7-8, 11)
  - Poems with Annotations by Colleagues, undated (Box 8)
  - Poetry Reviews by Julia Older, undated (Box 8)
  - Political Hellzapopping, undated (Box 118)
  - Reviews, 1940s-1950s (Box 14, 66, 110-111)
  - Reviews, 1960s-1970s (Box 54, 55)
  - Poem Revisions and Critiques by Agent Tom D'Evelyn, undated (Box 15)
- Series V: Photographs, 1937-2000
  This small series is composed of photographs of the Viereck family. The bulk of the photographs are undated.
  - "El Sitio"--Habana, Cuba With Unidentified Persons, undated (Box 115)
  - von Ende, Amalie, undated (Box 115)
  - Falkenberg, Betty, 1950s-1960s (Box 87-88)
  - Viereck, Peter and Mary Pinchot Meyer, undated (Box 1)
  - Viereck, Peter and Dorothy Grunes, undated (Box 6)
  - Family Photo of Mother and Children, undated (Box 9)
  - Viereck Jr., George S.--Army Photographs, 1940s (Box 83-85)
  - Viereck, Margaret Photograph Album, undated (Box 83)
  - Viereck Family, undated (Box 70)
  - Viereck, Peter--Portraits, 1937-1979 (Box 11)
  - Vierek, Peter with Family, undated (Box 14)
  - Viereck, Peter at Mount Holyoke, circa 1960s (Box 14)
  - General, undated (Box 21, 52, 71, 78, 80-81, 83-85, 87, 91, 115, 116,119-120)
  - Children on Horseback, undated (Box 21)
  - Portrait Photos, undated (Box 32, 95)
  - Printing Block, 2004 (Box 98)
  - Schnitzler,Arthur, undated (Box 118)
  - Sharpus, Deirdra, 1970s-1990s (Box 102)
  - Varoujan, Daniel Talk, 1985 (Box 63)
  - Viereck House, 1997-2000, undated (Box 61, 108)
  - Viereck House--Department of Environmental Management, 1967-1999 (Box 108)
- Series VI: George S. Viereck, 1903-1989
  Series VI contains an extensive and rich collection of papers relating to the life and work of George Sylvester Viereck. These files shed light on the complex relationship between Peter Viereck and his controversial father. There are important files on the trial and imprisonment of George Sylvester Viereck for violating the Foreign Agents Registration Act, as well as his correspondence, writings and interviews.
  - Accounts and Addresses, 1952-1960, undated (Box 115)
  - "All Things Human"--Reviews and Criticisms, 1950s (Box 112)
  - Articles, 1940s (Box 105)
  - Articles About George Viereck, 1950s, undated (Box 106, 112)
  - Articles Suggestions, undated (Box 119)
  - Autobiographical Interviews (Published and Unpublished), Statements and Clippings, undated (Box 119)
  - Autobiographical Stories, undated (Box 96)
  - Bank Books, undated (Box 120)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1921-1958, undated (Box 80, 96-97, 106, 115-116)
    - General--Jail 1942-1943 (Box 118)
    - Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1954-1955 (Box 106)
    - Baruch, Emmanuel, 1930s (Box 106)
    - Borchard, Edwin, 1938-1941 (Box 106)
    - Carr, Mrs. Donald, 1951-1953 (Box 106)
    - Chamberlin, J. E., undated (Box 106)
    - Colum, Padraic, 1943 (Box 106)
    - Cox, James M., undated (Box 106)
    - Crowley, Aleister, undated (Box 106)
    - Debs, Theodore, 1923 (Box 106)
    - de Grahl, G., 1923 (Box 106)
    - Dieckhoff, Hans Heinrich, 1938 (Box 106)
    - Harding, Warren, 1920s (Box 96, 97)
    - Hein, Margaret (Gretchen), 1934-1956 (Box 112, 116)
    - House, Edward Mandel, 1930s (Box 97)
    - Justice, Department of--Jail term, Sentencing, and Pardon, 1946-1953 (Box 106)
    - Lader, Larry, 1980 (Box 116)
    - Leonard, William Ellery, 1903-1932 (Box 97)
    - Milton, Bruce, 1955 (Box 115)
    - The New History Society, 1930s (Box 112)
    - Regarding "The Bankrupt," 1950s (Box 112)
    - Regarding "The House of Lesser Virtue," 1955 (Box 116)
    - Regarding War Propaganda, 1920s-1930s (Box 112)
    - Roth, Samuel, 1953-1956 (Box 115)
    - Viereck, George S. Jr.--Harvard Years, 1937-1940 (Box 21-22, 84-85, 87)
    - Viereck, George S. Jr., 1940s (Box 112)
    - Viereck, Peter--High School and Harvard Years, 1937-1942 (Box 21-23, 84-85)
    - Viereck, Peter, 1940s-1958 (Box 112, 115-116)
    - Viereck, Peter--Letter to George Bernard Shaw, 1938 (Box 84, 105)
    - While in Jail, 1942-1948 (Box 115)
    - With Agents, 1953 (Box 116)
  - Essays and Poems written at Harvard by Peter Viereck and George S. Viereck, Jr., 1937-1940 (Box 21-23)
  - General, undated (Box 112)
  - George Sylvester Viereck: German American Propagandist, by Niel Johnson, 1966 (Box 101)
  - Good Times--Stories and Articles, undated (Box 112)
  - Harry Benjamin, 1956 (Box 116)
  - Income Tax Information, 1960 (Box 116)
  - Income Tax Returns, 1958 (Box 116)
  - The Invincible Adam--Reviews, Synopsis, and Letters, 1930s (Box 112)
  - Journal--undated (Box 119)
  - The Kaiser on Trial--Press Clippings, 1937 (Box 98)
  - The Kaiser on Trial--Reviews and Letters (Box 112)
  - Letter from Die Zeit, undated (Box 32)
  - Listing of Autographs for Sale by George A. Van Nosdall, 1949 (Box 119)
  - Mailing Lists, undated (Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous Documents, 1944-1957 (Box 116)
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets and Clippings (Box 112)
  - Miscellaneous Receipts, 1957 (Box 116)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1910s-1989 (Box 112-114, 116)
  - Newspaper Clippings--German, 1920s (Box 115)
  - Newspaper Clippings--Judaism, 1933 (Box 115)
  - Newspaper Clippings--Post World War II, 1954 (Box 115)
  - Odyssey of a Barbarian--Biography of George Viereck, by Elmer Gertz, 1940-1978 (Box 106)
  - Paper--"Decadence to Decorum: George Sylvester Viereck and the Creation of a Poetic Community," By Lisa Szefel, 1994 (Box 106)
  - Passport (Box 120)
  - Photos
    - Undated (Box 112,119)
    - With George Bernard Shaw (Box 118)
  - Poems by Peter Viereck Dedicated to George Viereck, undated (Box 116)
  - Poetry Society of America, 1956-1957 (Box 116)
  - Promotional Materials and Articles About, 1943-1953 (Box 86)
  - Salome--Letters and Criticisms, undated (Box 112)
  - Testimony of George S. Viereck before the House of Representatives Sub-Committee on Un-American Activities, 1934 July 10 (Box 21)
  - Testimony, undated (Box 69)
  - Transcript of George S. Viereck, 1922 (Box 75)
  - Trial--Nazism, 1945 (Box 106)
  - Uncorrected Proofs for George Viereck's Entry in American Poet's 1880-1945, Third Series, 1986 (Box 105)
  - "The World of Arthur Schnitzler," 1972 (Box 114)
  - Writings, 1920s-1930s (Box 97)
    - Multiple Pieces, undated (Box 115-116)
    - Multiple Pieces--Poems, undated (Box 115-117,119)
    - Multiple Pieces Probably by George Viereck, undated (Box 115)
    - "The Anti-Christ," 1900s (Box 117)
    - "Bastille DC and Other Poems" (Box 119)
      - Personal Copy of George Viereck, undated (Box 119)
      - Copy for Gretchen Viereck, undated (Box 119)
    - "The Big Score," undated (Box 115)
    - "The Big Store" undated (Box 119)
    - "B.M. King of Dumbells, Prophet of Sex and Life," undated (Box 112)
    - "The Future of the Talkie," undated (Box 112)
    - Die Ballade von Reading Gaol Von Straefling 3.3 Frei Nach Oscar Wilde, undated (Box 119)
    - Downfall, undated (Box 119)
    - Du Un Die Masse, undated (Box 119)
    - Glimpses of the Great, 1930 (Box 106, 116)
    - The Harlot's House and Other Poems--Edited With Notes by George S. Viereck, 1925 (Box 77)
    - Here I Stand 1948 (Box 118)
    - The Impish Bulletin, 1929 (Box 80)
    - "Isaac Laguedem," undated (Box 115)
    - "London, Jack--The Ghost of Jack London," undated (Box 112)
    - "Maeterlinek, Maurice--Mankind Today and Tomorrow," undated (Box 112)
    - "Mann, Thomas--the New Paganism, Interview," undated (Box 112)
    - Men Into Beasts, undated (Box 77, 112, 115)
    - More Lives Than One--Autobiography, undated (Box 116)
    - "Mussolini, Benito--Mussolini Knew--Twelve Years Ago," undated (Box 112)
    - "My First Two Thousand Years," undated (Box 112)
    - "My First Two Thousand Years"--Reviews, undated (Box 115)
    - "My Flesh and Blood," 1931 (Box 115)
    - "The House of Lesser Virture" (Box 119)
    - "Nude in the Mirror," undated (Box 112,119)
    - Poems, 1900s, undated (Box 74, 96, 112)
    - Poems--Translated for Gretchen, undated (Box 105)
    - "The Poet in the Looking Glass," undated (Box 106)
    - "President Lazarus or Three Dead Men," undated (Box 112)
    - "Prince Pax," undated (Box 115)
    - "Rasputin, Mary--My Father Rasputin," undated (Box 112)
    - "Rejuvenation--Rejuvenation on by Radium; I was Rejuvenation—the Next Revolution," undated (Box 112)
    - "Rough Trade (Downfall)--undated (Box 119)
    - "Rupprecht, Crown Prince of Bavaria," undated (Box 112)
    - Russell, George--Interview, undated (Box 112)
    - "Science: What Will the World Be Four Hundred Years From Now?", undated (Box 112)
    - "Seven Against Man," 1940 (Box 115)
    - Spreading Germs of Hate, undated (Box 112)
    - Statements and Letters to the Editor, 1932, undated (Box 116)
    - "Strangest Friendship in History," undated (Box 112)
    - "The Temptation of Jonathan," 1937 (Box 112)
    - "Three Dead Men," By Sterling Warwick, undated (Box 112)
    - The Triumph of Life" (Box 119)
    - "The Virgin," undated (Box 119)
    - "The Vampire," undated (Box 119)
    - "Vampyr"--In German 1931 (Box 119)
- Series VII: Margaret Hein Viereck and Other Family Members, 1911-1979
  Series VII is comprised of personal documents belonging to Margaret and other Viereck family members. Birth certificates, diplomas, wills, passports, financial documents, and related correspondence are held in this series.
  - Correspondence
    - Mental Illness of Anya Viereck, 1957-1969 (Box 23, 83, 93)
    - Anya Viereck, 1940s-1950s (Box 78, 93, 96, 98,118)
    - Peter and Alexis Viereck, 1972-1974 (Box 23, 70, 80- 81)
    - Betty Falkenberg Personal and Publishing, 1954-1979 (Box 31, 87-88)
    - Viereck, Laura--Regarding Funeral, 1930s (Box 112)
    - Letters to Peter as a Child by Margaret Viereck, undated (Box 50)
    - Margaret (Gretchen) Viereck, 1911-1950s (Box 31, 52, 78, 80, 83-86, 95, 98, 112, 115-116,119)
    - Margaret (Gretchen) Viereck--Package from J. Ralph Jacoby, 1945 (Box 116)
    - Margaret (Gretchen) Viereck and Ben Lindas, 1944 (Box 112, 116)
    - Margaret Viereck and Peter Viereck, 1944 (Box 116)
    - Margaret Viereck--Postcards, undated (Box 116)
    - Personal Correspondence (Box 120)
    - Peter Viereck and George S. Viereck, Jr., 1933-1944 (Box 26, 34, 84-87)
    - Professional Correspondence Regarding Translations and Books (Box 120)
  - Divorce Documents--Anya Viereck, 1957-1969 (Box 23)
  - Document for Birth certificate on File for George S. Viereck, Jr. (Box 120)
  - Documents on the Death of George S. Viereck, Jr. (Box 26)
  - "On the Hop" by Margaret Viereck--Drafts and Critiques, 1931 (Box 30-31)
  - Essays by George S. Viereck, Jr., undated (Box 26)
  - "Etwas Neues," 1935-1936 (Box 113)
  - Financial Documents, undated (Box 75)
  - Household Diary--Instructions by Margaret Viereck Upon Her Absence--Account of Daily Activities of Peter and George Viereck Jr., 1933 (Box 80)
  - Interview with George Bernard Shaw for New York Evening Post, 1926 (Box 30)
  - One Fine Mourning--Play by Betty Falkenberg, 1970s (Box 78)
  - Photograph with George Bernard Shaw (Box 118)
  - Diplomas and Certificates (Box 26, 87)
  - Notes, undated (Box 80)
  - W--German Poetry Translations by Betty Falkenberg, undated (Box 47)
  - Alexis Viereck, undated (Box 114)
  - Margaret Viereck--Miscellaneous Documents, undated (Box 112)
  - Margaret Viereck Will, 1946 (Box 80)
  - World War Two Book for 28th Battalion--George S. Viereck Jr.--1942 (Box 80)
  - Writing by Betty Falkenberg, undated- (Box 81, 86)
  - Writing by John Alexis Viereck, 1973-1974 (Box 23, 48-49)
  - Writing by Margaret Viereck, 1940s (Box 70, 80)
  - Writing by Valerie Viereck, 1969-1971 (Box 51)
  - "Why I am An Optimist" by Albert Einstein, translated by Margaret Viereck, undated (Box 21, 50)
  - Baptism Documents, 1922, 1949 (Box 50)
  - Passport Documents, 1929-1979 (Box 61)
- Series VIII: Subject Files, 1935-2004
  Series VIII contains subject files concerning Peter Viereck and his family. This series is arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - General, 1955-1998, undated (Box 104, 106-107, 110-111, 113-114, 117)
  - Accordion Folder--With Letters and Addresses, undated (Box 115)
  - Adenauer, Konrad, 1976 (Box 113)
  - Anderson, Kathleen--Recommendation and Resume, 1980s (Box 104)
  - Andrews, Stuart--"Thomas Paine in France," 1989 (Box 102)
  - Anti-Defamation League, 1954 (Box 106)
  - Anvil Books, 1970s (Box 104)
  - Appendix, undated (Box 104)
  - Articles About Viereck, 1950-1971 (Box 113)
  - Articles and Papers by Various Authors, 1953-1988, undated (Box 100, 102-105-108, 110)
  - Anti-Left Articles, 1992-1998, undated (Box 110)
  - Arts Renewal with Reviews, 1950s-1970s (Box 104)
  - Author Information on Peter Viereck, undated (Box 117)
  - Autographs, circa 1970s (Box 105-106)
  - Bacon, Francis, 1975 (Box 103)
  - Baer, Amelia, undated (Box 103)
  - Baron VanGeen, undated (Box 112)
  - Bibliography--Peter Viereck, 1970s, 1985 (Box 102, 107-108)
  - Biological Time, 1965-1976 (Box 111)
  - Birthdays, 1953-1997 (Box 111)
  - Bloom, Harold, 1980 (Box 103)
  - Book Newsletters, 1987-1988 (Box 111)
  - Book Order Forms, undated (Box 104)
  - Book Reviews: New York Times by Michiko Kakutani, 1990s (Box 111)
  - Boston Globe, 1987 (Box 111)
  - Brodsky, Joseph--Memorial Service, 1980 (Box 94)
  - Buckley-Little Catalog (Box 111)
  - Cape Cod, circa 1988-1991, undated (Box 107)
  - Cassette Articles, 1984 (Box 111)
  - Catalogue of Rare Books Dealer G. A. Van Nosdall--Including Many Items Pertaining to Viereck Family, 1949 (Box 81)
  - Chamberlain, Houston Stewart--Bibliography, undated (Box 113)
  - Children Schools Documents, undated (Box 111)
  - Chocolate, 1998, undated (Box 111)
  - Clippings--Guest Lectures and Speeches by Viereck, 1950s (Box 49)
  - Clippings--Poland (Box 98)
  - Clothes and Measurements, 1995 (Box 111)
  - Conservatism Revisited British Edition Royalties, 1954 (Box 103)
  - Contemporary Authors, undated (Box 111)
  - "The Contemporary Soviet Woman: Combining Work and a Family"--by Diane Duvall, 1986 (Box 103)
  - Contracts--Miscellaneous, 1949-1977 (Box 113)
  - Contract with Higganum Hill Books, 2004 (Box 20)
  - Contract with Louisiana University Press for Metapolitics, 1979 (Box 18, 35)
  - Contract with W. W. Norton, Inc., 1982 (Box 113)
  - Copies of Correspondence Describing Russian Life, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Copyright Forms, 1976 (Box 113)
  - Copyrights, 1952-1993 (Box 113)
  - Cor Sheets, undated (Box 104)
  - Creative Conservatism Memos, 1970s undated (Box 104)
  - Critical Inquiry, 1970s (Box 103)
  - Deak, Istvan, 1990 (Box 104)
  - Dick, Philip--Poem in Commemoration of, 1983 (Box 64)
  - Dimension--Publication from the University of Texas at Austin, 1975 (Box 113)
  - Dispatch: Poets and Writers Bulletin, 1978-1984 (Box 103)
  - Documents from Event: "Twenty-Five Years After Peter Viereck's Conservatism Revisited" at Mount Holyoke, 1974 (Box 36)
  - Documents--Photocopies, undated (Box 111)
  - Eich, Gunter, 1969-1972 (Box 113)
  - Emmanuel College--Award to Peter Viereck, 1969 (Box 113)
  - Fischer, Ruth, undated (Box 107)
  - Forum, undated (Box 111)
  - Foundations--Other People, 1957, undated (Box 111)
  - Four Letters from Paris, 1953 (Box 102)
  - Frost, Robert--Quote, 1949-1955 (Box 106)
  - Frost, Robert--"Stopping By the Woods on a Snowy Evening" (Box 105)
  - Gary, Romain, 1980s (Box 103)
  - George, Stefan--Bibliography, 1998, undated (Box 113)
  - George, Stefan--Perilous Prophet, 1968, undated (Box 113)
  - Georgia Review--Clipping, undated (Box 113)
  - German Quarterly, undated (Box 113)
  - K. S. Giniger Company, Inc, 1960s (Box 104)
  - GM Questions, 1969-1970 (Box 100)
  - Goethe--Faust, 1976 (Box 113)
  - Goethe--Interview with Friedrick Riemer, 1946 (Box 113)
  - Goethe Writings, 1982, undated (Box 113)
  - The Gonne-Yeats Letters--Book Review, 1993 (Box 102)
  - Grant Applications, 1935-2000 (Box 64, 96)
  - Gunther, Johann Christian--Poem, undated (Box 113)
  - Health
    - After 50, 1992-1993 (Box 110)
    - Arthritis, 1966-1985 (Box 110)
    - Blood Pressure, 1991, undated (Box 110)
    - Brochures, 1989, undated (Box 110)
    - Correspondence with Veteran's Association, 1948 (Box 110)
    - Dental Work, 1993-1997 (Box 111)
    - Heart, 1972-1993 (Box 110)
    - History--Peter Viereck, 1976-1991, undated (Box 110)
    - Impotence, 1990-1993 (Box 111)
    - Intestines, 1967-1984 (Box 110)
    - Memory and Age, 1990-1991 (Box 111)
    - Morning Diet, 1987, undated (Box 110)
    - Prostate Gland, 1976, undated (Box 110)
    - Schizophrenia and Estrogen, 1981-1984 (Box 111)
  - Heaney, Seamus, 1989-1995 (Box 111)
  - Historiography, undated (Box 102)
  - History Classes at Mount Holyoke
    - Course 244--Final Exam, 1974 (Box 104)
    - Course s257--Assignments, 1969-1970 (Box 102)
    - Course 256--Exam and Syllabus, circa 1980s (Box 102)
    - Course 256--Paper by Janet Cromie titled "Peter Nikitich Tkachev: Jacobin Influence in the 1860s and in later Russian Revolutionary Theory," 1973 (Box 106)
    - Course 256--Paper by Colby Chapman titled "The Trial of Andrey Sinyavsky and Yuli Daniel," undated (Box 106)
    - Course 308--Reading List, undated (Box 103)
    - Course 310--Paper by James A. Gallivan titled "Yevtushenko: Conservative in Rebellion," 1972 (Box 108)
    - Course 350--Reading List, 1969-1978 (Box 106)
    - Course 350--Lysenko, undated (Box 106)
    - Course 350--Paper by Katherine Hermann titled "Yevgeny Yevtushenko: Knowing Which Way the Wind Blows in Soviet Russia," 1977 (Box 108)
    - Course 383--Paper by Kathryn Kirk titled "The Development of Russian Caesaropapism," 1962 (Box 106)
    - Course 384--Paper by Elizabeth Tannenbau, titled "The Sinyavsky-Daniel Trial," 1967 (Box 106)
    - Course 399--Paper "Vast, Impersonal Forces: The Masses in Modern Times," 1975 (Box 104)
    - Two World Wars and Two Totalitarians, 1980s (Box 113)
  - Hoelderlin, Friedrich "Menons Klagen um Diotima"--Translation, 1959 (Box 101)
  - Horace Mann Report Cards and Publications, 1932 (Box 87)
  - "The Ignored Lesson of Anne Frank," by Bruno Bettelheim, 1960 (Box 101)
  - Interview with Viereck by Harry Cargas, 1972 (Box 113)
  - Interviews with Viereck, 1990s (Box 6, 7, 20)
  - "Irish Nationalism"--Paper by Ellie McGrath for History 399, 1974 (Box 103)
  - Italian Lecture, 1954 (Box 84, 86)
  - Jonus, Manfred--"Isolationism in America 1935-1941, undated (Box 105)
  - Kipling, Rudyard--"The Man Who Was," 1980-1981 (Box 110)
  - Kohn, Hans--England's New Empirialism, undated (Box 102)
  - Kraft, Ken--Writings, undated (Box 111)
  - Krapp, Philip--With Writing, undated (Box 111)
  - La Clef d'Argent, 2002 (Box 110)
  - Lecture Engagements, 1963 (Box 113)
  - Lehman, David--Book Reviews for, undated (Box 111)
  - "Leontiev," by Nicolas Berdyaev, undated (Box 106)
  - Levels of Energy by David Bulwer Lutyens, 1965 (Box 70)
  - Literary Review--Spring 1988 edition, 1988 (Box 113)
  - The Louisville Cardinal, 1975 (Box 113)
  - "Making Room for Moderates: Louis Viereck and the Social Democratic Party in Germany, 1878-1890," by Lisa Szefel, undated (Box 106)
  - Mayakovsky, Vladimir--Paper on, 1986 (Box 106)
  - Metapolitics--Copyright, 1940s-1970s (Box 111)
  - Metapolitics--Notes, 1970s (Box 111)
  - Meyer--Law Article, 1977 (Box 106)
  - Modern Times--Paul Johnson, undated (Box 113)
  - "Moderne Welt," undated (Box 106)
  - Muller, Jerry Z.--The Other God That Failed, 1987 (Box 113)
  - My First Two Thousand Years--Movie Rights, 1960s (Box 106)
  - "The Mystery of Life," undated (Box 112)
  - Nabokov, V.--"Evening," undated (Box 106)
  - New England Poetry Club Golden Rose award--Peter Viereck, undated (Box 105)
  - New England Review, 1981, undated (Box 105)
  - New Letters on the Air--Promotional Catalogue for Poetry Readings, undated (Box 76)
  - New Letters Review of Books, Spring 1990 (Box 104)
  - New York Book Review, undated (Box 104)
  - Nominations for National Endowment for the Arts Award, 1989 (Box 38)
  - Nor Debate, undated (Box 107)
  - Notes by Viereck--General, undated (Box 107, 113-114, 117)
  - Notes from Viereck--Culture, undated (Box 104)
  - Notes between Viereck and others--regarding Conservatism, undated (Box 104)
  - Notes between Viereck and others--"Ending Youth," undated (Box 104)
  - Notes from Viereck, undated (Box 104)
  - Notes from a Writer's Conference, undated (Box 36)
  - Notification of Salary at Mt. Holyoke, 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - Odyssey Bookshop Consignment Form to Viereck, 1990s (Box 105)
  - Olsen, Tilly--Article About, 1974 (Box 111)
  - Option Agreement, 1974 (Box 105)
  - Other People's Writings--Some Notes by Peter Viereck, 1947-1981, undated (Box 70, 113-115)
  - Paglia, Camilla--Articles About, 1992-1994 (Box 111)
  - Pamphlets and Playbills, undated (Box 115)
  - Periodicals--With Notes, 1943-1985 (Box 98)
  - Permissions to Use Poetry, 1970s (Box 77)
  - Pettingell, Phoebe--"Anthony Hecht's Design," 1990 (Box 111)
  - Photos for Rus, undated (Box 106)
  - Poems About or To Viereck, 1962-2004 (Box 35-105)
  - Poetry in Britain, 1987 (Box 103)
  - Poetry Reading and Mailing Lists, 1988 (Box 117)
  - Poetry Reading at University of Missouri, undated (Box 8)
  - "Police," 1981-1984 (Box 106)
  - Population Dynamics, 1950s (Box 103)
  - Populism, 1975, undated (Box 104)
  - Pornography, undated (Box 90)
  - Press Releases, 1940-1964 (Box 81, 83, 86)
  - Professional Record, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Program for Poetry Reading at Harvard, 1982 November 18 (Box 14)
  - Program for Poetry Reading at University of Missouri, 1985 January 22 (Box 13)
  - Program from "Staging the Third Reich" (Art Exhibit), 2002 (Box 18)
  - Prospectus of Grant Project on George Santayana and Bernard Berenson, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Psychological Warfare Roster, 1985 (Box 36)
  - Publications List, 1992 (Box 20)
  - Publishers to Buy Books From For Classes (Box 119)
  - Purchase Orders--Peter Viereck, circa 1985 (Box 106)
  - Quine, W. V.--Obituaries, 2000 (Box 105)
  - Radio Liberty Committee--Broadcasts in Russian, 1964 (Box 70)
  - Rebuttals, circa 1970s (Box 103)
  - Rief, Phillip, "Fellow Teachers," 1972 (Box 111)
  - Rockefeller Grant Files, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Rockefeller Grant Project Notes, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Royalties, 1970s-1990s (Box 105)
  - Royalties--Greenwood Press, 1978-2001 (Box 113)
  - Royalties--Records of Payments, 1976-2002 (Box 96)
  - Russia--Peter Viereck's 1962-1963 Trip, 1962-1963 (Box 106)
  - Russia-Peter Viereck's 1968-1969 trip, 1968-1969 (Box 106)
  - Russian Diary, 1962-1963 (Box 72)
  - Russian Movies, undated (Box 106)
  - Russian Poems, undated (Box 106)
  - Sakharov, Andrei--Writings By and Writings On, 1973-1990 (Box 107)
  - Sandburg, Carl--Writings, 1950s undated (Box 105)
  - Sexton, Anne-- Sylvia's Death, 1963 (Box 118)
  - Shapiro, David--Clippings, 1970s (Box 111)
  - Sharpus, Dierdra, 1994 (Box 102)
  - Shaw Itinerary, 1926 (Box 105)
  - Sheridan House, Inc.--Royalty Statements, 1999-2003 (Box 106)
  - Simonov Clippings, Notes, and Correspondence, 1964-1972 (Box 106)
  - Sinyavsky, Terz, 1960s-1970s (Box 105)
  - Soviet Literature Conference Papers, 1962-1963 (Box 12, 44)
  - "Stevens Revisited," 1948 (Box 105)
  - Student Course Evaluations, 1989 (Box 63)
  - Student Papers, 1974, undated (Box 62, 81, 90)
  - Surkov, Alexei, 1959, undated (Box 106)